Are you okay sharing the unit with someone else?
Hi. I'm Lorelei Rios.
Loki Mendez.
What was that incident you're running away from?
I feel like we're gonna be BFFs.
Here he goes again.
I need to report this.
Looks like I went into the wrong room.
I believe I can help you.
Because of some worthless guy.
Take back what you said!
I want you to join the Q.E.D. Club.
Ma’am! Sir!
You're not allowed to be here.
Come down now.
If anything happens to you here, the school will be accountable.
Does your silence mean yes?
You're really something, huh?
Is this a prank?
Of all people, why did you pick me to join your detective club?
The Student Council wants to shutdown Q.E.D. Club.
They said there aren't any other members.
My club needs to have another member
or else, they’ll take away my club room.
Okay, so why is that my problem?
You're right.
It’s not your problem.
It’s the favor you owe me.
In exchange for helping you with Linda.
Her name is Lisa,
not Linda.
Also, of all the things you could ask me,
why did it have to be this?
Is there nothing else?
I mean, I don't know.
I can run you some school errands or get you one month free coffee.
- Or something... - Unless, you can give me my own club room.
I don't need those.
The Student Council Vice President is bullying me.
He knows it will be hard for me
to pursuade anyone
to join my club.
That's why he ordered the shutdown.
Look, whatever your issue is with the Student Council VP,
that’s none of my business.
But I can’t join the Q.E.D. Club.
Because I don't know anything about solving mysteries.
I’m not meant for that.
But you have a talent for writing.
Right?
You have a blog.
Yes?
So what?
The Q.E.D. Club is the perfect avenue
to showcase your journalist skills.
Just saying.
Today, he asked me to join his club.
I don't even know why I told him I owe him a favor.
After all, he's the one who actually wronged me.
Loki?
♪ Shadows. ♪
♪ Creeping slowly through the dark. ♪
♪ Watching, blocking, like. ♪
♪ You can't even take a step. ♪
♪ Every cry, every shake. ♪
♪ Only walls reflect the ache. ♪
♪ All the echoes burn inside. ♪
♪ Like fire and bullets in the past. ♪
♪ Listen to the warnings. ♪
♪ Threats are drawing near. ♪
♪ This is not the world you thought. ♪
♪ You would know. ♪
♪ Listen to the warnings. ♪
♪ Open up your eyes. ♪
♪ This is not the world you thought. ♪
♪ You would know. ♪
♪ Listen to the warnings. ♪
Act normal.
Okay.
Lori.
Why?
What's your problem?
What...
Sorry, Tita.
- What, do you think I'm a ghost? - No, Tita. I’m sorry.
I just get startled easily, that's all.
How was your sleep?
You might be lacking rest.
That's why you're jumpy.
You know how staying up late messes with you, kids.
Acutally, Tita...
I feel kinda uncomfortable here.
That’s why I can’t fall asleep right away.
Do you want me to change your mattress or pillow?
Oh, no need.
My pillow and bed are fine.
It’s just...
I think I hear rustling in the ceiling and walls.
That’s why I can’t fall asleep.
But maybe it’s just my imagination, so don’t mind me.
I'm not trying to make you more scared, but I just want to tell you that…
I hear noises at night, too.
Huh?
Really, Tita?
So it's not just my imagination?
That’s what the other tenants told me too.
What can I do?
I don't know how to deal with spirits.
This place's already been blessed.
Three times already. But it’s still the same.
Maybe that’s the reason
why no one stays long
in your unit with Loki.
They say the loudest creaks are in your unit.
But don't worry,
because I always include all my tenants in my prayers.
That’s why I’m sure,
it's just creaks, that's all.
Because
you’re all protected by my prayers.
Oh, Tita, I have to go now.
I'm sorry. Bye!
What if bad luck is actually chasing me?
Or worse, what if I’m the bad luck?
It's like every world I step into...
I end up messing things up.
When will this ever end?
I can't believe I'm entering this room again.
The same room that witnessed how Aaron stalked me.
I’m new here, and I’m already in trouble again.
Okay, guys. Settle down.
Go back to your seats.
It's only been a few weeks this semester, guys,
but we already have a lot of issues.
Put yourselves together, huh?
Focus on your studies.
Not just on things that stress you out.
Yes, sir.
Attendance call.
Byron, Kelvin?
Present, sir!
- Dela Cruz, John Paul? - Present!
Flores, Aaron?
Sorry, I forgot.
- Galang, Mary Jane? - Present, sir!
Jocson, Lisa Claire?
Sir, she’s absent today because of yesterday’s incident.
Roque, Aina?
Present!
- Reyes, Von Andy? - Present.
Girl, just a reminder, the org application deadline's on Friday.
You have to decide.
Is it really mandatory to join the org?
Of course!
What else are you gonna do here, just study?
That'd be so boring.
And didn't the dean say orgs cover 30 percent of our grade?
That'd be such a waste if it happens.
Okay, fine.
But I was hoping for something more chill.
How about you?
What org did you join?
Oh, I'm switching clubs.
I didn’t like the club I joined last year.
Why?
There’s no thrill, Gardening Club.
Like, I don’t know if it’s just me or what.
But it feels like they're training me to be old.
I'm still young. Why turn me into a plantita at this age?
So I feel like it has a purpose and everything.
But going to class?
I want something with thrill,
something that excites me when I go to school.
Something that will hype me up.
You know, we can join the Paranormal Club together...
Sure, Rosetta. Let's join the Paranormal Club.
Yeah, Lori. That'd be fun, right?
Especially if we're together and there's a thrill.
Perfect. Right?
Yeah! I'm in. I'll hand in my application. We can go together!
Sorry!
No. It’s okay.
- I’m new here. - Oh, okay.
I’m just looking for Foreign Affairs Office.
Oh, okay.
Well, I’m also new here.
But I think it might be in the other building.
Oh, thank you so much.
Oh, okay. Yeah.
- Well, I see you around. No problem. - Yeah. See you!
Hi. Join our club, okay?
Hi. Maybe you'd like some of our flowers?
Maybe you want tomato???
There are more here.
Come, join!
Hi. Join the Cyber Club.
Please join the Cyber Club!
Clarion?
Okay, I'll think about it. I have to go.
Okay.
Young Traveler's Club.
- Lori! Why did you leave me at the locker? - Rosetta.
Sorry. I thought you were following me.
Come on. Let's join here. Let's go!
There are many demons here.
Come on! Let's go inside!
Hi!
- Look. - What's this?
Paranormal Club!
Come on. Let’s join this.
Hold on. It's just...
I’m not sure yet. Besides, I don’t have a third eye.
Even with just two eyes, it's fine. You can still join our club.
That's right. Stay here. It’s fun here.
Yeah, this is very thrilling.
They've got ghost-hunting activities.
Come on, let's join.
Can you be more careful with that?
What if that hit me?
Why?
Did it hit you?
It didn’t, right?
You’re not my target.
Whatever!
As expected...
you won’t see me in the club room.
And you'll still go home early.
No way.
I just really want to rest.
Why?
Maybe you're wondering.
I transferred my work place here.
Since they're kicking me out of the club room very soon.
I need to try to find a new place
where I can continue my work.
Thanks to you.
Are you mad?
Is that why...
you're picking on the photo of that innocent guy?
Nope.
The word "innocent" doesn't suit him.
He’s anything but innocent!
The word "despicable" suits him better.
If you run into this person in the hallway,
you better hide.
I'm tired.
I'm going to sleep.
Later.
My club needs to have another member.
Or else, they’ll take away my club room.
A true journalist
is someone who does not just report
but exposes the truth.
The truth about what affects us, the public.
Unfortunately, the exposition isn’t enough.
Things need to be well-researched,
investigated
and in all angles.
This is my dream for all of you.
You are the next generation of storytellers
who are committed to the truth
and it is backed up by facts.
So for your activity,
let us put into action
everything we discussed about research.
Think of a story
that piques your interest.
And of course, when you submit and present it,
make sure it's backed up by research.
Ma’am!
What type of topic?
Anything!
Something that sparks your curiosity.
Understood?
Yes, ma'am.
All right. Now, go to your groups.
What if we make the emergence of AI our topic instead?
If it’s okay to use in school or at work.
Advantages and disadvantages.
Yeah, right.
But I heard the other group is also doing AI.
What about you, girl? What do you think?
Seriously? What if we think of a new topic?
How about you, Lori?
Do you have any topic in mind that the other groups haven’t thought of?
Hmm...
What if..
Mental health?
Right? It’s relevant, after all.
Especially after all the incidents.
For example, what happened with Lisa.
Maybe we can focus on..
What are the usual signs
that a person struggling with his or her mental health?
Basically, the importance of this research is to inform
and to give awareness to everyone.
So that if they have loved ones
who are struggling,
they’ll know how to handle it.
I feel like we’ve got our topic. Perfect!
I know right, girl!
Yeah. Let’s go with that one.
Nice one!
Sounds good. Let's go?
- Let’s start? - Yeah.
Alright.
That’s Lori!
- Yeah, you’re right! - Come on! Let’s go to Lori!
Excuse me!
Lori!
Hey!
Why are you eating by yourself?
- I thought we were having lunch together. - Hi, Lori!
Sorry!
I got hungry.
We’ll join you.
So, have you chosen a club to join?
I haven’t decided yet.
Since you’re still having a hard time deciding,
come join me in the Paranormal Club for now.
- Yeah! - Yeah!
- Come on, join us. - Yeah, Lori.
It's fun.
Since there are more of us now,
and I’m sure I’m transferring there,
it won’t be scary anymore.
There are many of us.
Plus, didn’t you say you wanted something chill?
See? It’s chilling.
- Promise. - Chilling.
Are you guys really sure about the Paranormal Club?
Don’t you want the Q.E.D. Club?
- Huh? - That’s an adventure, too.
- I don’t want there. It feels weird. - Right.
That club’s probably cursed or something.
It only has one member.
Ah, maybe no one joins because it’s cursed.
You think so?
Wait.
Are you sure you’re really hunting a ghost?
Yes!
Maybe there’s really nothing to hunt.
Sometimes there’s nothing. But sometimes there is!
They said before the main quest,
the club has to do a dry run at a haunted apartment.
- Really? - Yes.
Someone actually suggested a hunting spot.
He used to live there.
It’s just three blocks away.
But...
he had no choice but to move out.
Three blocks away.
Isn’t that Tita Martha’s apartment?
The story goes that when he’s taking a bath,
he says he hears someone calling his name.
And asking for help.
Right?
There’s more.
When he’s asleep...
he hears banging and rustling sounds.
Oh, scary!
What's the name of that apartment?
They said it’s Henson Apartment.
Are you okay?
I’m okay, but...
Henson Apartment?
I'm sorry to tell you, but there’s no ghost there.
Maybe it was just his imagination.
What makes you say that?
Because I live there.
I’ve been there for almost a month.
Nothing's happened to me.
Oh, really?
Yeah. Nothing at all.
Even...
my roommate.
He said he hasn’t felt any ghost there.
You can’t be sure either.
Maybe there really is something.
You just didn’t explore enough.
Yeah, maybe you’re just in denial.
Exactly!
Maybe once we bring the equipment,
that’s when things will show up.
I really don’t want to.
They do have a point.
Come on.
Join us.
Join us already.
Come on.
Come on, Lori.
Lori!
Lori! Lori! Lori!
Lori! Lori! Lori! Lori!
Lorelei...
Tita Martha?
Lori...
Help me, Lori.
Lori!
Help me, Lori!
Tita Martha, why?
Lori! Help me, Lori!
Oh, my God.
Don’t you ever rinse?
I hear something.
It sounds like an old woman’s voice.
It’s calling out my name.
It’s asking for help.
There’s nothing in there.
You’re just tired.
Loki, I promise, I really hear something.
Ghosts don’t exist. Okay?
But...
Okay.
Nevermind.
I believe you.
Thanks.
Why is it me?
Why is it asking me for help?
What kind of help can I give
if I can't even help myself?
Honestly, I'm scared.
I don’t want to believe that woman’s voice.
But if I ever believe it...
I hope it's your voice I hear.
- My child... - Why is it me?
Smile.
That’s it.
Show me your teeth. Beautiful smile!
Why is she asking me for help?
How can I help someone, if I can’t even help myself?
I don’t know what to do without you, Mom.
I miss you.
Lorelei, help me. I'm begging you.
What is it now?
I heard an old woman’s voice
in my room.
Why?
What are you laughing at?
I’m serious, Loki.
It's true!
It's almost 10:00.
Just sleep it off.
It'll go away.
Are you sure?
You really don’t see
or hear or feel anything strange?
Mind over matter.
If you really believe there’s a ghost, then you’ll see one.
So annoying.
My God.
Help me, Lori.
Please leave me alone.
Whoever you are.
Lori.
Help me, Lori.
I'm begging you, too.
Let me sleep.
If you want, go bother my friend Rosetta instead.
Lori...
Help me, Lori.
Lori. Help me, Lori.
Lori...
I...
I'm begging you.
Lori. Help me, Lori.
Help me, Lori.
Lori...
Lori. Help me, Lori.
Lori.
Help me, Lori.
Lori. Help me, Lori.
Lori.
- Whose hair is this? - Lori.
Lori. Help me, Lori.
Over and over again.
Same intonation.
Same stress in the syllables.
Lori. Help me, Lori.
Recorded.
The voice is recorded.
Lori.
Lori. Help me, Lori.
Lori. Help me.
Have you gone mad?
Mad?
Yes, I’m really mad at what you did!
What did I do to you?
Don’t mess with me, Loki.
What you said was right.
Ghosts don't exist in this unit.
See?
Told you.
But what the old woman’s voice I hear when I’m showering
and while I'm in the room...
that was you, wasn't it?
I don’t know what you’re talking about.
Please enlighten me.
Really?
Then how would you explain this?
What is that?
So I found a strand of hair on my floor, just a minute ago.
It’s only about two to three inches long.
There’s no way that came from my hair.
It’s too long, and the color’s different!
It’s not Tita Martha’s either,
since her hair’s kind of long.
Of the three of us who have access to this unit,
only you could own this.
Are you sure?
What does that have to do with the voice you heard in your room?
This is proof you were in my room
and you planted the tape recorder under my bed!
You recorded your voice and distorted it,
so would sound old and I wouldn’t recognize it.
Lori.
Help me, Lori.
Lori. Help me, Lori.
Lori.
You wanted to scare me, so you did that, right?
When you hid that tape recorder under my bed
you didn’t expect for me to find a strand of your hair.
Did you?
Now that I think about it...
your previous roommates experienced the exact same thing.
So…
is it possible that you played the same prank on them
to make them move out
so you could have this whole unit to yourself?
What?
Am I right?
Bravo!
I did not expect you to figure it out
in a matter of hours.
And just to be clear,
it was my intention
to leave a strand of hair in your room.
I want to know if you’ll be able to notice it
so you can connect it to the tape recording.
And...
you failed to disappoint me.
Think of it as a test.
- Test? - Yeah.
To scare me?
So you can force me out of this unit?
Part of it, yes.
I want to know
if you deserve to stay in this unit.
And...
I want to know...
if my hunch about you is correct.
What hunch?
That you
have above average observation skills.
While I was reading your blog,
I noticed how detailed you were in describing every moment.
You never let anything slide.
I find that very impressive.
So why?
What do you need to confirm?
That you deserve...
to join my club.
The result of my test on you
made me want to recruit you more.
Recruit my foot!
Oh!
So you’re rejecting my offer?
Is that why you’ve been avoiding me since yesterday
at school and even here in the apartment?
Excuse me, I'm not avoiding you!
Are you sure?
Based on the actions you’ve shown...
you are showing an Avoidance Behavior.
What are you even saying?
It’s a form of defense mechanism
where a person avoids certain situations
that cause stress, fear, and uneasy emotions.
Oh, my God, can you please stop psycho-analyzing my actions?
Also, can you ask me for a different favor instead?
Let’s not talk about me joining the club.
If you keep insisting on what you want
sorry, but I can’t give it to you.
Did you hear me?
I said no!
Yeah, I heard you.
But you’re leaving me with no other choice.
What do you mean?
How dare you!
Delete that!
How did you get that?
You went into my room without my permission?
You should have installed more locks on your door.
Look at your photo.
You probably won’t like it if this spreads on social media.
Are you blackmailing me?
Am I?
It doesn’t matter to me as long it does the trick.
Loki, I'm telling you!
I dare you!
I dare you.
Loki!
That’s a threat, you know.
But you know what, go ahead.
Post it.
I don’t care.
I’m not threatening you.
I’m just reminding you of your promise.
You said that you’re willing to help Lara.
Lisa!
Whatever.
But whoever that student is...
you told me to help her.
Because you feel guilty
when you don’t help her.
You felt somewhat responsible.
Now, all I’m asking for is what you said.
Are you really like that?
You can’t keep your word?
You can’t keep your word, Lorelei?
Loki’s like my ghost, he never leaves me alone.
I may not like his attitude,
but everything he says is true.
Which really scares me.
A lot.
I admit it, I’m afraid of being judged.
I’m scared my life will get messed up.
I’m scared the truth will hit me hard.
But despite all these fears,
there is one thing true.
I want to help others.
I may not able to face my own fears,
but perhaps I can help others face theirs.
Focus on your studies and stay out of trouble at school.
Okay.
Just do it, Lori.
Loki?
Loki, are you there?
To: Rhea Subject: Just checking on you.
Message: How are you doing?
It's been three weeks since I sent my last email to you.
And you still haven't gotten back to me.
Either you've been too busy to check
or you don't open your e-mail as regularly as I do.
In any case,
I'm writing to express how the status quo bores me.
Without you,
this world lacks the colors it once had when you were around.
It has become dull and monotonous.
I wonder how long I can endure the mundane.
Of all the people who know me,
you are the most aware
of how much I abhor the dismal routine of existence.
Everything is so ordinary.
Everyone is so boring.
And everything is so grey.
I’ve been searching for an added tinge of color in my life.
But it has always escaped my grasp ever since you left.
You would surely agree with me
when I say that I need to find a distraction.
An escape from this repetitive and depressing reality.
If you were only here,
it would still be a lot of fun and challenging.
I always found your opposition to my views thought-provoking.
Now...
I’m in a constant pursuit of diversion
to keep my mind stimulated and my monsters at bay.
It may be an endless chase...
and I don’t know if it’s a worthwhile quest, but...
this is the best alternative I have so far.
I look forward to hearing your stories.
Please get back to me as soon as you can.
Regards,
Loki.
Your curiosity would have you killed!
Do you know that?
Why did you just suddenly show up?
I don’t remember giving you permission to read my personal messages.
That's a clear invasion of privacy!
Yeah, right!
Coming from someone who was peeking at my messages
while I was reading them.
And someone who comes into my room late at night
to take pictures of me while I was sleeping
without my consent.
You’re probably here to join the Q.E.D. Club.
Here’s the form.
Fill it out.
Are we good?
Okay, quick orientation.
The Q.E.D. Club
is the one and only detective club in Clark University.
Its name is derived from the Latin phrase,
Quod Erat Demonstrandum.
Which means in English,
“Which was to be demonstrated."
That’s usually placed at the end of math proofs
or philosophical arguments
to show that you’ve proven what you set out to prove.
Okay.
Thanks for the info.
So, what should I do?
Well...
our mission is to investigate hidden truths...
solve mysteries through logic and teamwork
and protect the innocent from deception and injustice.
Noted.
For your role, it’s pretty simple.
You will help me collate requests from clients.
Once we’re in the investigation proper,
I expect you to provide insights.
I need you to observe more in the case details,
crime scenes,
the people involved, their stories and et cetera.
And of course...
don’t forget to take down notes so we won’t miss anything.
So...
once we solve the case…
your main task is to write about it
and post it on your blog.
Wait.
So are you saying…
you want me to be the club chronicler?
Something like that.
As you may notice
the Q.E.D. Club isn’t popular yet
among the students,
freshmen and transferees.
We can use your writing skills
to advertise our club.
Boost our popularity
and attract more clients.
So as Vice President,
you are in charge of media and public relations.
Wait.
I’m the club Vice President?
I didn’t sign up for this.
I’m the President of this club.
So as a second member,
by default,
you’re the Vice President now.
For now, we will wait for a client
to come and tell us their story.
Or if you don’t have the patience to wait...
you can leave.
I’ll message you when we have a case.
Your contact number is in the form anyway.
So, that's it?
You actually joined the Q.E.D. Club?
I’m really sorry, Rosetta.
I’m just not really into paranormal things.
Too bad.
But if you change your mind, let me know, okay?
It’s fun there. I promise.
Alright.
Thank you, though.
No problem.
But, wait.
Are you still going to continue your ghost hunting at Henson Apartment?
I’m telling you, there are no ghosts there.
You’ll probably just end up disappointed.
Exactly. We’ll just look for somewhere else.
Oh, no! Our class is about to start!
Huh?
Let’s go!
Why didn’t the lunch bell ring?
Did you hear it?
I didn’t either.
Maybe it's broken?
Come on.
Let’s go.
Hurry! Hurry! Let's go.
Come on, we’re late for the next class. Ma’am is already there.
Oh, no. What's that? What's happening?
- It's so crowded. - What happened?
Why is everyone freaking out?
Excuse me.
Come on, let's check it out.
We’re going to be late.
Just for a second.
Get them out of here!
Go back to your classrooms!
Go back! Go back! Go back.
- Go back to your classroom. - Go ahead.
Go back to your classroom.
- Go. Come on. - Go back, go back.
Go back.
Consider this our first official case together.
I'm Chief Gareth Estrada.
Don’t just stand there.
We got some work to do.
Have you seen this, Chief?
According here...
Isaac texted three people with the same message.
I called you here because your president was found dead.
Does that mean...
he was killed to silence him?
Look, the post already has a lot of reactions and comments!
What happened to him?
Why is he like that?
Lorelei Rios?
Be honest with me.
Were you forced to join that club?